In this video, we're gonna continue our discussion of bottom-up parsing with the
在本视频中，我们将继续讨论自下而上的解析
main strategy used by all bottom-up parsers, so-called shift-reduce parsing.
所有自下而上解析器使用的主要策略，即所谓的Shift-Reduce解析。
Here is a quick review of the most important thing that we learned last time,
下面是我们上次学到的最重要的东西的快速回顾，
that a bottom up parser traces a right most innervations in reverse. Now this
自下而上的解析器反向追踪最右侧的神经。现在这个
particular fact has an important consequence. So let's think about a state
特定的事实具有重要的后果。那么让我们来考虑一下一个州
of a shift reduced parse where we have string alpha, beta and omega, and let's
我们有字符串alpha、beta和omega，让我们
assume the next reduction is going to be the replaced beta by X. Okay, so remember
假设下一次减少的是X替换的测试版。好的，所以请记住
we're running productions backwards. Then I claim that Omega has to be a string of
我们在倒排制作。然后我断言欧米茄必须是一串
terminals. And why is that? Well if you think about it, if this is a rightmost
终端。为什么会这样呢？如果你仔细想想，如果这是最正确的
innervations in reverse, then when X is replaced when we take this if we look at
相反的神经，那么当X被替换时，如果我们看一下
the forward step is the, the backward step. So remember the parser is running
前进的一步就是后退的一步。所以请记住解析器正在运行
this way replacing data by X. But if we think about the rightmost innervations in
这种方式将数据替换为X。但是如果我们考虑一下中最右边的神经
the other direction then X has to be the rightmost non-terminal, which means there
那么X的另一个方向必须是最右边的非终结点，这意味着在那里
are no non-terminals to the right of X and so all the Character, all the tokens,
在X的右侧没有非终结符，所以所有字符、所有令牌
whatever it is in this string have to be terminal symbols. Now it turns out that
这个字符串中的任何内容都必须是终端符号。现在事实证明，
those terminal symbols to the right of the right most non-terminal are exactly the
最右侧的非终端右侧的那些终端符号恰好是
unexamined input in bottom of parsley implementations. That is if I have alpha
欧芹实现底部的未经检查的输入。如果我有阿尔法的话
X, omega and I'm, and X is my right most to non-terminal then this is the input
X，omega和我，X是我最右边的非终端，这是输入
that we haven't read yet. This is unexamined Input And it's gonna be useful
我们还没有读过。这是未经检查的输入，它会很有用
to mark, where we are, in the parse, where our, where our input focus is. And we're
来标记我们在语法分析中所处的位置，以及我们的输入焦点所在的位置。而且我们正在
gonna do that by using a vertical bar. So we're gonna just place, drop a vertical
我要用竖条来做到这一点。所以我们要把垂直的
bar. Between the place where we read everything to the left, and we've actually
酒吧。在我们阅读左边所有东西的地方和我们实际上
been working on this. So this stuff to the left here can be terminals and
一直在做这件事。左边的东西可以是终端，
non-terminals and we, the parts that we've seen all of that stuff. And the stuff to
非终端机和我们，我们看过所有这些东西的部分。以及要做的事情
the right is after the parts hasn't seen. Now we don't know what's out there,
右边是零件还没见过的地方。现在我们不知道外面有什么，
although we do know its all terminal symbols. An d the vertical bar is just
虽然我们知道它都是终端符号。竖线正好是
gonna mark the dividing line between the two sub-strings. To implement bottom up
将在两个子弦之间标出分界线。要实施自底向上，请执行以下操作
parsing, it turns out we only needs two kinds of actions. Shift moves and reduce
解析后发现，我们只需要两种操作。移位、移动和减少
moves. And we've already talked somewhat about reduce moves, and so we have to
动起来。我们已经在一定程度上讨论了减少移动的问题，所以我们必须
introduce shift moves. So let's do that now. So a shift move, reads one token of
引入换班动作。那我们现在就开始吧。因此，换班移动时，会显示一个令牌
input. And we can explain that or represent that by moving the vertical bar
输入。我们可以解释这一点，或者通过移动竖线来表示这一点
one token to the right. So if our input focus is here, and we want to read one
右边有一枚代币。因此，如果我们的输入焦点在这里，并且我们想要读取一个
more token of input, then we just move the vertical bar over. And this signifies that
更多的输入标记，然后我们只需将竖线移到上面即可。这意味着
now the parser knows about that next, terminal symbol. And now we can start
现在解析器知道了下一个终端符号。现在我们可以开始
working on it. It can do things. We can match against it for the purposes of
我正在努力。它可以做一些事情。我们可以与之相匹配的目的是
performing reductions. Again the stuff out here to the right of the vertical bar the
执行减量。再说一遍，这里竖条右边的东西
parser hasn't seen yet. And then a reduce move is to apply an inverse production at
解析器还没有看到。然后，Reduce移动是在以下位置应用逆积
the right end of the left string. So if in production a goes to xy and we have x and
左弦的右端。所以如果在生产中a转到xy，我们有x和
y here immediately to the left of the vertical bar. So this is our focus point,
这里就在垂直条的左边。所以这就是我们关注的焦点，
okay, and x and y the right hand side of the reduction is right there. Then we can
好的，x和y，减去的右手边就在那里。然后我们就可以
do a reduction, we can replace that right hand side by the left hand side, and this
做一个缩减，我们可以把右手边换成左手边，这就是
is a reduce move. Here is the example from the last video, and this is exactly the
是一种减少行动。下面是上一个视频中的示例，这正是
example just showing the reduced moves, now with the vertical bar also shown. So
示例中只显示了减少的动作，现在还显示了竖线。所以
this shows where the input focus was, at the point where each of the reductions was
这显示了输入焦点所在的位置，也就是每个减量所在的点
performed. And what's missing, of course, now we know, is the sequence of shift
已执行。当然，现在我们知道，缺少的是移位的顺序
moves. So here is the sequence of shift moves and reduce moves that, take the
动起来。下面是Shift移动和Reduce移动的顺序，
initial input string, to the start symbol. So let's walk through this in more detail.
初始输入字符串，设置为开始符号。因此，让我们更详细地介绍一下这一点。
So we're going to go step by step. And we're going to show each shift and each
所以我们要一步一步来。我们将展示每个班次和每个班次
reduce move. And now in addition to our input string down here we also have a
减少移动。现在，除了这里的输入字符串之外，我们还有一个
pointer showing where the where in the input we are. So initially we haven't seen
指示我们在输入中的位置的指针。所以一开始我们还没有看到
any of the input, and our input pointer is to the left of the entire str ing. So the
任何输入，我们的输入指针位于整个字符串的左侧。因此，
first move is to do a shift. And then we do another shift, and then we do another
第一步是换班。然后我们再做一次轮班，然后我们再做一次
shift. And now just look at the example from before if you look back at that, at
换档。现在看一下前面的例子，如果你回头看的话，
that example, you know, the next thing we need to do is to reduce. So remember we're
这个例子，你知道，我们需要做的下一件事是减少。所以请记住我们是
only allowed to reduce to the left of the arrows. So, we can only reduce over on
只允许减少到箭头的左边。所以，我们只能减价了。
this side of the arrow. So, we always have to read enough of the input before we can
箭头的这边。因此，我们总是必须先阅读足够的输入内容，然后才能
perform a reduced move. And then we perform another reduce move, okay? And
执行减少的移动。然后我们再做一次减速动作，好吗？和
then it turns out the next thing to do is two shift moves and we haven't explained
那么接下来要做的就是两个轮班动作，我们还没有解释
yet how we know whether to shift or reduce we're going to get there. I'm just showing
然而，我们如何知道是转移还是减少，我们就会到达那里。我只是展示一下
that there exists a sequence of shift and reduce moves that succeed in parsing this
存在一系列的Shift和Reduce移动，它们成功地解析了这个
example. Now we've shifted the entire input onto this sorry we've, we've. We
举个例子。现在我们把所有的投入都转移到这个抱歉上了，我们。我们
shifted over the entire input, so there's no more input to read. And now all we can
移动了整个输入，因此没有更多的输入可读。现在我们能做的就是
do is reduce moves. But fortunately, there is a sequence of reduce moves from this
要做的就是减少动作。但幸运的是，从这一点开始，还有一系列的缩减举措
point, that we can we can perform. So, here we reduce int, and then we reduce T
这一点，我们可以，我们可以表演。所以，在这里我们减少INT，然后我们减少T
plus T. Oh, forgot, we first reduce T to E, and then we reduce T plus E back to the
加T。哦，忘了，我们先把T减成E，然后再把T加E减回
start symbol.
开始符号。